# Paul Schorey

# **Technical Expertise**

Languages: JavaScript, ¡Query, SQL

Frontend Technologies: React, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap Mobile Development: React Native, Apache Cordova

Tools: Git, NPM, Babel, CLI, AWS (S3, Cloudfront, Lambda), Xcode, Android Studio, Sublime Text

Misc. Skills: SEO / ASO, Browser Compatibility, Site Optimization, In-App Purchases and Advertising Monetization

Strategies

# **Projects**

# **Best Typing Lessons**

I created this as a website for my students using JS, jQuery, PHP, and SQL, but have since updated it and adapted it to work as an iOS and Android app while also being able to be hosted as a website on AWS using one codebase. The app has been downloaded over 120,000 times and has an average iOS rating of 4.65 / 5.

## App Ratings and Review & Track and Field Scorebook

iOS apps created and published using React Native. Makes use of Apple Connect REST API, Realm DB, XML and JSON parsing.

### **Farmer Math**

Website created using React JS and converted into a Cordova app for proof of concept. Makes use of AWS Lambda to dynamically update questions as needed and incorporates Firebase analytics.

# Other Apps & Websites

Various other projects that incorporate Node.js, Chart.js, Data Tables, Google Analytics, Unity3d, C#, and other technologies.

View More Details At: <a href="https://www.squadtiming.com/about/index.html#projects">https://www.squadtiming.com/about/index.html#projects</a>

# **Professional Experience**

#### Norwell Middle School Teacher 2012 - Present

Instructor of Computer Applications, US History, and College and Careers courses. Successfully navigated in-person, remote, and eLearning situations. Served in multiple committees: COVID Task Force, Safety Committee, High Ability Program, New Building Design Committee, and National Junior Honor Society.

### East Allen County Schools Substitute Teacher 2011 - 2012

Substitute teacher highly sought after due to diligent work ethic, dependability, strong teaching ability, and positive interactions.

### The Crossing Educational Center (High School Alternative Education Teacher) 2009 - 2011

Educated and set course and graduation goals for students in the credit recovery program.

### **Verizon Sales and Customer Service Representative** 2007 – 2009

Call center sales and billing support specialist.

# **Coaching**

#### **Assistant Football Coach** 2016 - 2020

Specialized as the defensive coordinator. Emphasized being people of good character on the field and in life

### **Head Track and Field Coach** 2012 – 2020

Grew teams from under 70 athletes to over 120 athletes each season (20% of the student body). Oversaw five assistant coaches. Created a positive goal focused culture with high expectations for coaches and athletes

# **Education**

Master of Divinity Moody Theological Seminary - Chicago, IL

Bachelor of Science in Secondary Education Indiana University – Fort Wayne, IN